Engaging and collaborating with our
stakeholders.
Remember, it's our job to build
relationships with our stakeholders.
Engage and involve them so they support
our project.
So engaging stakeholders is a very
important role for the PM.
So we have to set expectations.
We do that, especially when we're defining
the scope and creating the WBS.
then we have to manage
stakeholder expectations as
we're going along and
influence their expectations.
Based on constraints
imposed on us, not everything's
going to make it into the project, often.
So we'll have to manage and influence
stakeholder expectations.
And it's our job to build we
and our team, job to build
trust with us, and amongst
the other stakeholders.
We address concerns and issues with the
stakeholders.
Any issues they're having, we need to
manage.
We'll be communicating the disposition of
those change requests.
All right.
So the more we can communicate with them
still has to have a purpose.
You don't just communicate and send out
stuff.
All right, but this is to address their
concerns.
Let them know what's happening on our
project.
So we had to develop the strategies to
involve and engage the stakeholders based
on their needs, expectations, interest,
and potential impact on our project.
That's why we had to know who they are and
then categorize them.
All right.
So collaboration and communication can
build trust between the parties.
Of course it does.
So we have to monitor overall stakeholder
relationships.
We need to create.
an atmosphere of mutual trust,
build those relationships, show them how
the project will benefit them, get
them to support our project, all right?
So we'll be monitoring overall stakeholder
relationships and and we'll adjust
strategies and plans to keep the
stakeholders engaged.
So an exam tip, if a new major stakeholder
is identified on the project, best choice
for the PM will be to engage the
stakeholder, communicating with them
directly, finding out their
needs and expectations,
and not just waiting
for them to come to us.